Marat Saytakov · Senior iOS Software Engineer · Résumé · CV

My name is Marat Saytakov. I am an iOS software engineer with over 5 years of experience. I am proficient in Objective-C, but I prefer Swift.

I graduated from Moscow State Technical University, where I studied computer science and microchip programming. I have an <u>Engineer's degree</u> in Information Systems.

Currently I live in Moscow, but I am ready to relocate for the right position.

Contact

email: <u>remarr@gmail.com</u> GitHub: <u>m4rr</u>

website: <u>m4rr.ru</u> LinkedIn: <u>maratsaytakov</u>

Skills

Deep knowledge in Objective-C and Swift, Core Animation. 99% crash-free apps.

Short-list: iOS SDK, UIKit, M/ARC, GCD, WebSocket, CocoaPods/Package Manager, Git, CI, Unit Testing, Profiling Instruments, Design Patterns, OOP, Apple HIG. C, Ruby, Go.

Employment

Independent Consulting · iOS development · 2015—Present

WirelessHeads · pasteapp.me · Lead iOS Developer · Oct. 2015—Present

Co-founder in a startup. We made Paste—pretty cool clipboard manager for OS X. I was working on Paste for iOS—mobile clipboard manager, synchronized with OS X app.

- architected a framework to sync data between Paste apps, based on iCloud CoreData;
- developed a multi-platform adapter to unify OS X AppKit and iOS UIKit classes;
- designed a great user experience of iOS app, related to Apple HIG.

Luuk · <u>luuk.com</u> · Lead iOS Developer · Oct. 2014—Sep. 2015

Luuk is the top beauty-industry startup in Moscow. In just a one year I released two apps which are completely different and both loved by users.

- implemented such a great and complex UI/UX design smoothly with top-speed FPS;
- production Swift codebase;
- 30k installs in the first month and 99% crash free users.

RocketBank · rocketbank.ru · iOS Developer · Sep. 2013—Sep. 2014

Released a RocketBank based MVP of a card-to-card mobile application, as well as developed the second version of <u>RocketBank app</u> with a fellow programmer.

Aic · aic.ru · iOS Developer · Aug. 2012—Aug. 2013

Prototyped a mobile app for <u>Money Inc</u>, a future banking concept. It is a simple way to manage your banking accounts.

Self Employment · <u>m4rr.ru</u> · Developer · 2008—2012

Made projects using pure C, Parser, JavaScript and Objective-C (since iOS 5).

Public Activity

Apple Swift contributor on GitHub · github.com/apple/swift · 2016

I started contributing to Swift with small things.

Code Mentor · codementor.io/m4rr · 2015—Present

I am a code mentor, covering expertise of Swift, plain C, Objective-C and Xcode.

Moscow Coding School · moscoding.ru/ios · 2015—Present

Mentoring students at an in-person Swift programming course.

CocoaHeads Moscow · 2013—Present

Active member of Moscow iOS/OS X developers community. Given talks:

- iOS Custom Keyboards (2015, round table)
- <u>Size Classes</u> (2014, in Russian)

Side Projects

Moscow Underground Wi-Fi Auth · m4rr.ru/mauth · App Store · GitHub

Everyone in Moscow Metro has to waste a lot of time to get authorized thru over-complicated Wi-Fi Captive Portal. I solved this problem: this app takes care of authorization process for the user. Retention rate 50%, very popular in Moscow.

Chars · chars.cc · App Store

Beautiful and native way to type everything with Unicode characters on iOS.

Easy Percent · App Store

An easier and prettier calculator for taxes and reverse percentages.

Education

Engineer's degree in Information Systems at the Faculty of Cybernetics in Moscow State University of Radio-engineering, Electronics and Automation (MIREA has H+ rate) September 2007—July 2012